therealnews.com 2019-08-08

# TRNN Personal Data Security and Privacy Practices

Dear Members, Supporters and Viewers of The Real News Network,

We are sending out this message to update our current privacy policy in light of the new GDRP Privacy Rules initiated by The European Union that go into effect this month.  Our supporters are extremely important to us and therefore, so is their data.

**TRNN Privacy Policy**

This policy applies to all information received by TRNN, both online and offline, across any platform, including electronic, written, or oral communications.

**What Data does TRNN Collect?**

_TRNN collects and maintains the following data:_

  * Contact Information: name, address, telephone number, email address
  * Giving History: gift amount, date, any gift restrictions requested by the donor
  * Information on events attended, publications received, any special requests for program information
  * Browser data including information about your operating system, hardware data, and browser version when submitting online forms.

_TRNN does not store the following data:_

  * Payment information including credit card numbers or bank accounts.

**Online Data Transmission – New Website**

All data transmitted between you and the TRNN website is now SSL encrypted.

**Data Storage**

All data about our donors (see list above) is stored using Raiser’s Edge NXT, a cloud-based software developed for nonprofit fundraising.  For more information regarding the data policies of Raiser’s Edge, you can visit <https://www.blackbaud.com/general-data-protection-regulation>.

All donation transaction data is processed and stored by Click & Pledge, an online fundraising platform for nonprofits.  For more information regarding the data policies of Click & Pledge please visit <https://clickandpledge.com/privacy/>

**Data Usage**

Donor information collected by TRNN and stored using the above mentioned methods is also used to analyze giving patterns in order to make accurate budget projections.

Browser data is only used for website diagnostic purposes

_TRNN will use confidential donor information for the following purposes:_

  * Distributing donation receipts
  * Sending thank you letters to donors
  * Informing donors of TRNN news and events
  * Internal analysis and record keeping
  * Contacting donors about changes to in policy

**Use and Disclosure of your Personal Information:**

  * We will not sell, share, or trade your personal information with other entities without your permission.
  * We will not send you mailings on behalf of other organizations.
  * We may collect your name, email address, telephone number, and payment information when you make a contribution, either on our website, over the phone, at an event, or by mailing in a check.

**Consent**

Your continued use of offline and online features of TRNN relating to your data will let us know that you’ve accepted these updates to our privacy policy.

**The Right to be Forgotten**

If you have questions about this TRNN Privacy Policy, or if you wish to be removed from our databases, please contact our Data Privacy Officer at stephenrfrank@therealnews.com.

**Future Changes to TRNN Privacy Policy**

We reserve the right to change this TRNN Privacy Policy in order to provide you with the best possible data security practices.  When we do, we will note the last update at the bottom of the policy.
